Now that we've cleaned our movies and reviews datasets,
清理了 movies 和 reviews 数据集后
let's get started with our first type of recommendation.
下面我们创建第一种推荐系统吧
So, the way that I went about solving this was to create a helper function,
我创建了一个辅助函数
which I called create ranked df,
称之为 create_ranked_df
that takes in the movies and reviews dataframes,
它会接受 movies 和 reviews DataFrame
and then returns the ranked movies.
并返回 ranked_movies
This ranked movies item,
然后将 ranked_movies
I would then pass to the popular recommendations.
传递给 popular_recommendations
So, I create this create rank dataframe function which takes in the movies and reviews,
我创建了这个 create_ranked_df 函数 它会接受 movies 和 reviews
and essentially I just want to return a dataframe of the ranked movies,
我想返回一个 ranked_movies DataFrame
which then I'm going to pass here.
并将其传递到这里
So now the popular recommendations is basically just going to pull these parts,
popular_recommendations 将提取这些部分
and I'm going to worry about these things within this function.
我需要在此函数里实现这些标准
So I want to input these two items,
我将输入这两个数据集
and I'm going to take care of all of these parts within this function.
然后在此函数里实现这些部分
The first thing I'm going to do is I want to create this movie ratings
首先我将创建这个 movie_ratings 对象
object which basically groups by the movie ID.
它会根据 movie_id 对电影分组
A lot of times when I'm creating these functions,
在创建这些函数时
I'll do a lot of the work outside of the function and then just move
通常我会将很多工作放到函数外面
it in and as I know what's happening.
然后在知道发生什么时再移进来
So, if we take the reviews,
获取 reviews
and if we look at this again,
再看看该数据集
screen in the dataset.
糟糕 读取下数据集
So, if we look at the head of this dataset.
看看此数据集的标题行
Basically what I want to do is for each movie,
对于每部电影
I want to look at the average ratings.
我都要查看平均评分
So, for the first part of this,
也就是第一个标准
I want the movie with the highest average rating.
我要获取平均评分最高的电影
So, for each movie,
对于每部电影
I'm going to group those together and then get the average highest rating.
我将这些组合到一起 并获取平均评分最高的电影
So, I'm going to group by the movie ID,
按照 movie_id 分组
and I basically care a lot about this rating part.
我对这个评分部分很感兴趣
So, I'm just going to store that in something called movie ratings.
所以将它存储到 movie_ratings 中
If we look at that, that's just going to be a groupby object right now,
现在它将是一个 groupby 对象
but I can do lots of things with that.
但是我可以对它执行很多操作
So, one thing that I might do is I might take
例如 可以求均值
the mean and what that does is it gives me the average rating for each movie.
这样就能得出每部电影的平均评分
Or I could take something like the count,
或者运行 count()
and that'll give me how many times that particular movie was rated.
这样就能获得这个电影的评分次数
So, we can see that this movie was rated 417 times,
可以看到 这个电影被评分 417 次
this one was rated twice,
这个被评分 2 次
a lot of these were only rated once.
很多电影只有 1 个评分
So, now I want that within my function.
现在将这行代码放入函数中
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create this thing average ratings,
我将创建这个 avg_ratings
that mean that we saw,
它等于刚刚看到的均值
and I'm going to create num ratings,
然后创建 num_ratings
which is basically the count you just saw.
它等于刚刚看到的计数
So, with this, we can get the highest average rating.
这个可以获取最高平均评分
We're looking at movies with more ratings are better.
然后是评分更多的电影更好这条标准
So, this count will help us keep track of how many ratings there were.
这个计数将跟踪有多少条评分
We also want to have a minimum of five ratings.
还需要评分至少达到 5 条
So, we need this num ratings part for that.
这条标准需要用到 num_ratings
Then if the average and the count are the same,
如果平均评分和评分计数一样
then the ordering should look at how recent they were.
那么需要根据新近情况排序
So, I want to get something that tells me how recently this movie was rated.
所以我需要知道电影评分的新近情况
So, we still want to group by the movie ID,
依然需要根据 movie_id 分组
and then we can look at the max of the date column.
然后查看日期列的最大值
This max pulls the most recent movie.
这个 max() 会提取最近的电影
So, that can be a little confusing,
这里有点难理解
but the min is like the oldest movie and the max is the newest movie.
min() 表示最早的电影 max() 表示最新的电影
So, this information can then be used to tell us if
如果两部电影的平均评分和评分数量一样
two movies are tied in terms of average rating and the number of times they were rated.
这部分信息能够告诉我们如何排序
So maybe they're both have an average rating of 10,
或许两部电影的平均评分都是 10 分
but they've only been rated once.
但是评分都只有一条
Then the movie that we want to rank higher is the one that was rated most recently.
那么评分最新的电影排名更高
So, I'm going to take that information.
我将利用该信息
Let's see.
我们来看看
I'm going to take this information and use it as well.
我将使用此信息
From here, I just want to merge a lot of this information together.
然后将所有这些信息合并到一起
So, I'm going to create this ratings count dataframe,
我将创建这个 ratings_count_df
which is going to have one column for the average rating,
它有一列是平均评分
the average movie rating,
平均电影评分
which I'll just call average rating,
我将称为 avg_rating
and then it's going to pull the average ratings we created right here.
然后提取在这里创建的 avg_ratings
Then num ratings is going to be another column and it's going to pull those values there.
另一列是 num_ratings 它将提取这些值
So, you can imagine what this thing is looking like.
可以想象这个 DataFrame 是什么样的
It has one column for this,
它有一个这样的列
it has another column for this,
还有一个这样的列
and then it's storing those values that were created within it.
并且存储了我们创建的这些值
Because of the way we pulled this,
对于我们的提取方式
unfortunately, we can't just add it the way that we added these.
遗憾的是 不能直接这样添加这些值
So, instead, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a dataframe out of this,
我将在这里创建一个 DataFrame
and then I'm just going to create the name of
然后创建列名称
the column to be exactly what we have up here to be consistent.
使其与这里的完全一样 保持一致
So, what this is doing is it's creating this dataframe.
这行代码将创建这个 DataFrame
It just has the ID as the movie ID.
它的 ID 为 movie_id
So, that's the index on this and then the column is going to hold
这是它的索引
all the last ratings which are basically all of those dates that we
这列将存储所有最后的评分
just saw with the column heading as last rating.
也就是列标题为 last_rating 的列中的日期
So, what I'm going to do from here is basically take
在这里 我将这个 DataFrame
this dataframe and join it with the last rating dataframe.
与 last_rating DataFrame 连接到一起
So, I'm going to take this dataframe that we just
我将刚刚创建的这个 DataFrame
created and join it with this dataframe that we're creating here.
与在这里创建的 DataFrame 相连接
When we just do a joining,
在连接时
it's going to look for the index to be the same.
它会查看相同的索引
So, the index on the rows to be the same and just match those two things up.
行上的索引要一样 将二者匹配到一起
Then, you might be wondering we did all of this with
你可能会疑问
the reviews and that basically takes care of all of this stuff.
刚刚对 reviews 执行的所有这些操作已经处理了所有这些标准
The reason why we need the movies
为何还需要 movies 数据集
dataset is then to pull some information about the movie.
原因是为了提取电影信息
So, what we want to do is we want to rank things by
我们将使用刚刚创建的这些新列
these criteria using these new columns we just created,
根据这些标准对电影排序
but then we want to pull information from the movies dataframe like the title
然后从 movies DataFrame 提取信息 例如标题
to be able to pass that back in this popular recommendations function.
并将这些信息传递给 popular_recommendations 函数
We're going to want to join the movies dataframe.
我们需要连接 movies DataFrame
In order to do a join similar to what we did before,
为了像之前一样连接两个 DataFrame
I'm going to set the index to be the movie ID.
我将索引设为 movie_id
So, we want to basically take this and just the same way that we joined this,
我们将像这里的连接方式那样
we can join these together.
将这两个连接到一起
So, we can join this new movies
我们将这个新的 movies DataFrame 与这个连接到一起
dataframe with the movie ID as the index with this because it'll have the same index.
索引为 movie_id 因为这个的索引也一样
I'm just going to call that movie recs.
称之为 movie_recs
So, if we look at the header of this,
看看这个表格的标题
you'll see it has the movie ID and this has the same movie ID.
它有一个 movie_id 这个也有相同的 movie_id
So, we're just going to basically join these two tables together
我们将根据 movie_id 将这两个表格连接到一起
on that movie ID so that we have an average rating, the number of ratings,
这个表格包含平均评分、评分数量和最后评分时间
and the last time it was seen linked to the actual movie title,
然后与实际的电影片名相关联
as well as all of these other things about
以及所有其他关于电影的信息
the movie and the case that we want to use them.
以防我们想要使用这些信息
Then basically, what we want to do from here is create
接下来
this ranked movies dataframe which
我将创建这个 ranked movies DataFrame
is going to basically be the joining of these two parts.
它会将这两部分连接到一起
So, you can see that's how this works by simply passing in just that.
直接在这里传入 movies
So, if we do this,
运行代码后
we get them all linked together.
将它们都关联到了一起
So, you can see those three columns here and the movie.
可以在这里看到这三列 还有 movie 列
So, that's essentially what we're storing in this movie recs.
这就是 movie_recs 中存储的内容
Basically, what we want to do then is just sort this by the criteria that we set.
然后根据设置的标准排序
So, first, we want to sort it in the way that this works,
所以首先我们需要排序
if you go look at the documentation on sort values is
看看 sort_values 的文档会发现
it ranks by the first thing that's in the list first.
排序原理是按照列表中的第一项排序
So, the first thing we want to do is rank by the average rating.
所以首先按照平均评分排序
Then basically if there are ties in the average rating,
如果平均评分相同
then we want to rank by the number of ratings.
则按照评分数量排序
Then if there are ties with that,
如果评分数量也相同
we want the thing that was ranked most recently to be ranked first.
则按照最近排序的项排序
As an argument, this takes ascending equal to false.
参数设置为 ascending = false
On this last part, it says we want a minimum of
最后一个条件是 评分数量如果不超过 5 条
five ratings in order to be considered amongst the best.
则不能被视为最佳电影
So, if a movie doesn't have five ratings,
所以 如果电影没有 5 条评分
then we don't consider it.
则不考虑该电影
So, the num ratings here is greater than 4, then we'll consider it.
如果 num_ratings &gt; 4 则考虑该电影
So, I'll pull the ranked movies where the number of ratings as more than 4 and then
我将提取出评分数量超过 4 的已排名电影
basically those are the actual ranked movies that I want to return back.
这些就是我要返回的实际排名电影列表
So, a little complex,
我已经演示了整个过程
but we walked through all the steps.
流程有点复杂
Hopefully, that makes some sense.
希望你能听明白
Then basically we're passing this part in.
将这部分传入函数中
So, now it's the easy part.
下面的步骤比较简单
So, essentially, in this function,
在此函数中
all we need to do is return the top movies.
我们只需返回 top_movies
The top movies is just going to be a list of the n top movies.
top_movies 将等于一个有前 n 部电影的列表
So, we already created this ranked movies thing that we're passing in here.
我们已经创建了在这里传入的 ranked_movies
Then basically we just want to grab the movie title,
我们需要获取电影片名
and we're going to pull n top.
并提取 n_top
So, ranked movies is already assorted dataframe.
ranked_movies 是已经排序的 DataFrame
We're going to pull the movies that are already sorted
我们将提取已经排序的电影
and we're going to pull this many of them and return them as a list.
并且将提取这么多 然后返回为列表
It's because I'm forgetting to store it here.
糟糕 在这里忘了存储它了
Lets see. I joined these,
我们来看看我连接了它们
but then I didn't store it in this.
但是没有在这里存储它
Therefore, when I joined it here,
所以当我在这里连接它时
it didn't have that column on it. Lets see.
没有这一列我们来看看
Great. That should be fixed now.
Great问题应该解决了
Great. So, going back up here,
Great回到这里
it looks like it all ran,
看来代码能运行
everything stored, and then it looks like it passed all the tests which was good.
一切都存储到变量里了 并且通过了所有的测试 不错